Guide to the Papers of Nicholas Wahl MC 146
New York University Archives
- Series II: Correspondence
  - "Europe '73 Correspondence", 1973 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - "Europe Take 1977-1978", 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Fa - Fe, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Fi - Fu, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - "Fellowships 69 - 72 - Sources", 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - "Ford Louvain 68 - 69 Personal/Univ.", 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - "Foundations, SSRC, Grants, etc.", 1967 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - "Fr. 77 - 78", 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - "Fr. Pol. Corresp.", 1967 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - "France - Speeches & Visits 67 - 68", 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Frank MS - Legislatures in Changing World", undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Jim Freedman MS", undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Friedrich, C.J. "CJF Dinner", 1971 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Fulbright: "Early Fulbright & Paris Housing Corresp.", 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fulbright: "Official Fulbright Corresp. 67", 1967 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Ga - Gl, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Go - Gu, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Gendrot, Sophie Body, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The German Marshall Fund "Marshall Fund - Fr. Lang. Program", undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Goguel, François, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "Graziano, Luigi" (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - "Graziano, Luigi" (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - "Grenoble 82", 1982 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Guggenheim, Michel, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Ha - He, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hi - Hy, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - "Harvard 72 -73", 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Hoffmann, Stanley, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - "Hyman/ATT Speech", 1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - I, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Image de la France Conference, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Institute of the Humanities, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - "IFS Recommendations - current 90", undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Ions, Edmundo, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - "Jean Monnet Council", 1987 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Judt, Tony, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - J, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - K, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - "Kramer 69 - 72" (folder 1 of 2), 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - "Kramer 69 - 72" (folder 2 of 2), 1969-1972 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Kramer, Steven, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "Melvyn Krauss", undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Lab - Law, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Lec - Lew, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Li - Lu, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "Lemerle & 58 d'Assas letters etc.", 1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "Leontief," Wassily, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Letter Archive 76 - 77", 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Lille Jan. 78", 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Lops," Bryan, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mab - Maz, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Mc - Me, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Mi - Mu, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Maus, Didier, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "Maxwell", 1961 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Mény, Yves "Lavau Mélanges", 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - "Merite 10/91, Legion of Honor 1/31/86, Academie Morale & Pol. June 82", undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Metzgar, Hal, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Milton, Mary (Council on International Educational Exchange), undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Mitterrand, François, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Morel, Thomas, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Morse, Ed, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Mueller, Susanne, undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - "Muskie - Europe 1971-72", 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - N, undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - "New York - USA letters - May '95 (IFS etc.)", 1995 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Nora, Pierre - letter & accompanying enclosures, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - "NYU Students & official business March 1986" (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - O, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Office corresp. Jan. 69 - June 70" [Princeton] (folder 1 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - "Office Corresp. Jan. 69 - June 70" [Princeton] (folder 2 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "Office Corresp. Jan. 69. - June 70" [Princeton] (folder 3 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Office Corresp. Jan. 69. - June 70" [Princeton] (folder 4 of 4), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "Oliva Feb - March 85", 1985 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "O.U.P." (Oxford University Press), undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - P - Pe, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Pi - Pi, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - "Paris 63 - Pol. Corresp. DeG, Debré, etc.", 1963 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - "Paris - Spring 63, Jan. 64 Pol. & Personal", 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - "Paris June 69", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - "Paris - Oct. 74", 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - "Paris, Oct. 76", 1976 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - "Paris March 77", 1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - "Paris June 77", 1977 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "Paris May - June 79", 1979 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - "Paris '3' 79 - 80", 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - "Paris June 1980" (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - "Paris - Nov. 80", 1980 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - "Paris - March 1981" (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - "Paris - June 81", 1981 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - "Paris - Nov. 81", 1981 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - "1982 Paris 4 Students" (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - "Paris March 82", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - "Paris, Spring '82", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - "Paris Spring/Summer 82", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - "Paris 83 Archive", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - "Paris Feb. 83", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - "Paris Return May 83", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - "Paris - Spring '83", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - "Paris Spring & Summer 83", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - "Paris Nov. 83", 1983 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - "Paris March 84", 1984 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - "Paris/London June 1984" (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - "Paris Nov. - Dec. 84", 1984 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - "Paris April 85", 1985 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - "Paris July 85", 1985 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - "Paris March 86", 1986 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Paris Corresp. March 86", 1986 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - "Paris May 86", 1986 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "Paris Dec. 86 - June 87", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "Paris March 87", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "Paris - Nov./Dec. 87", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "Paris Dec. 87", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - "Paris, Spring 88", 1988 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "Paris March 89", 1989 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - "Paris April 90", 1990 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "Paris June '90 & London Aug. 90", 1990 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - "Paris Sept. '93 - current letters", 1993 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - "Paris Fall '93 Real Estate Apartments", 1993 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - "Patterns 1st & 2nd eds", 1954-1971 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - "Patterns 3rd ed", undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - "Personal Mail June '96", 1996 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "Petrie Chair", 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - "President's Reports 66", 1966-1976 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - "Princeton - 63 - 64 Job Corresp.", 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - "Publishers", 1956-1967 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - "Publishers & Articles", 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - "Publishers Inquiries - 71", 1972-1977 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Q, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - R - Ri, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Ro - Ru, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - "Reid Hall - Grad Institute", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - "D. Rémy - 71", 1971-1977 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - "République - Correspondence", 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - "Rockefeller/Bellagio investature", 1971 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Roelker, Nanny, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Rogers, Susan Carol, undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Ross, George, undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - "Gail Russell", undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Sa - Sch, undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Se - Sm, undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - So - Sz, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - "SAIS March 72", 1972 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Schonfeld, William, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Shapiro, Judith", undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - "Speeches Spring 82", 1982 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - State Department USA, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Summer '74 ---- on Hasey & SF10", 1974 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - T, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Tallahassee 65", 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - de Tarlé, Antonine, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Tempesta," Lelio, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "Tempesta, Lelio - Confindustria", 1975-1978 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Thatcher, Sanford, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Le Theule, Joël, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Thompson, Dennis, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Tiersky, Ron, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Touchard, Jean, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Tuck, Edward Hallam, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - U, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - UNESCO, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "UK letters - May '95 & Finances - Sept. '95", 1995 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - "USA Correspondence - March '86", undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "USA letters", 1977, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - V, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - "Vitae - NW & Model Fletcher", 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Wa -Wh, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Wi - Wz, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Wahl, mother of, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Warnecke, Steven, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - "WCHS Film Series", undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "Webster, Ann" (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Webster, Ann" (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Williams, Philip, undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - World Economic Reform, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - X, Y, Z, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - unidentified, undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - unidentified, undated (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - unidentified, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
- Series III: Political Party Information
  - Parti Socialiste S.F.I.O.: Publications, 1945-1949 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Political Publications, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Political Publications, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Mouvement Républicain Populaire (M.R.P.): Publications, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mouvement Républicain Populaire (M.R.P.): Publications: Fichier du Militant, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Parti Radical et Radical-Socialiste (Parti Republic Radical et Radical-Socialiste): Publications, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Mouvement Républicain Populaire (M.R.P.): Publications, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Mouvement Républicain Populaire (M.R.P.): Publications: Forces Nouvelles, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Parti Socialiste S.F.I.O.: Publications, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Elections: élection législative complémentaire du 7 decembre 1952 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Political Publications, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Parti Communiste Français (P.C.F.): Publications, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Elections: élections municipales du 26 avril 1953 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Mouvement Républicain Populaire (M.R.P.): IXe Congrès National, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Parti Socialiste S.F.I.O.: 45e Congrès National, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Political Publications, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Political Publications: France Indépendante, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Société Nationale des Entreprises de Presse: Publications, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - The National Association of Labour Student Organizations (NALSO, U.K.): Publications, 1955 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Elections: élections législatives du 2 janvier 1956 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - l'Union pour le Salut et le Renouveau de l'Algérie Francaise (l'U.S.R.A.F.), l'Union pour le Renouveau Francais (l'U.R.F.): Publications, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Elections: élections législatives partielles du 13 janvier 1957 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Fédération internationale des droits de l'homme: Publications: Les Cahiers des Droits de l'Homme, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Parti Radical et Radical-Socialiste: 54e Congrès National, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Union et Fraternité Francaise (U.F.F.): Congrès National, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Political Publications, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Comité(s) de Salut Public (C.S.P.): Publications, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Elections: élections législatives des 16 et 30 mars 1958 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Elections: élections législatives des 23 et 30 novembre 1958 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - The Labour Party (U.K.): Publications, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Parti Socialiste S.F.I.O.: Publications: Bulletin Intérieur, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Political Publications: Socialist Commentary, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications, 1959-1962 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Italian Political Parties: Publications, 1959-1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Parti Socialiste: Publications, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The Conservative Party (U.K.): 81st Annual Conference, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - The Labour Party (U.K.): 61st Annual Conference, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Political Publications: "The Common Market debates (U.K.)", 1962 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications, 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - The Liberal Party (U.K.): Publications, 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - The Conservative Party (U.K.): 82nd Annual Conference, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The Labour Party (U.K.): 62nd Annual Conference, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Political Publications, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications: Rapport sur les Attitudes des Français dans la perspective d'élections présidentielles, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Political Publications, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Elections: élections municipales du 14 mars 1965 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Elections: élection présidentielle du 5 decembre 1965 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Political Publications, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Political Publications: revue française de sociologie, 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Political Publications: Les Forces Politiques, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Parti Communiste Français (P.C.F.): Publications, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Political Publications, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Club Jean Moulin: Publications, 1967-1970 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Esprit: Le Congrès Esprit 1968 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Political Publications, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Elections: élection présidentielle, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Political Publications, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Polication Publications, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - l'Unité des Socialistes: Congrès 1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Political Publications: Problèmes Politiques et Sociaux, 1972-1981 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Parti Communiste Français (P.C.F.): Publications, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Parti Socialiste: Congrès National 1973 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Political Publications, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles du 5 mai 1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Political Publications: Le Gouvernement et les Ministériels, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Foundation Européenne pour l'Économie (F.E.E.): Publications, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Political Publications, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Political Publications, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Parti Socialiste: Congrès National 1974, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Parti Socialiste: Convention Nationale, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Parti Socialiste: Publications, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Parti Socialiste: Publications: l'Unité, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Political Publications, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Political Publications: Les Cabinets Ministériels, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Rassemblement pour la République (R.P.R.): Publications, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Political Publications: actualités service, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Elections: élections législatives de mars 1978: Le dossier du candidat (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Elections: élections législatives de mars 1978: Paris (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Elections: élections législatives de mars 1978: Publications (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Elections: élections législatives de mars 1978: La Sarthe (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Parti Ouvier Européen: Publications, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Political Publications, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Union pour la Démocratie Française (U.D.F.): Covention Nationale, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Buttons and Badges, 1970s (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Elections: European Election, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles: English Publications, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Political Publications: Sablé et Erve et Vègre, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Elections: élections minicipales de mars 1983: Paris (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Elections: élections minicipales de mars 1983: La Sarthe (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Parti Socialiste: Publications, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Political Publications, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Political Publications: "Interviews with Mauroy and Mitterrand", 1983 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Political Publications, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Elections: élections des députes et conseillers régionaux de mars 1986: La Sarthe (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Political Publications, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: Raymond Barre (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: Jacques Chirac (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: Pierre Juquin (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: André Lajoinie (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: Jean-Marie Le Pen (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: François Mitterrand (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Elections: élections présidentielles des avril et mai 1988: Publications (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Political Publications, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Political Publications: Les Cabinets Ministériels, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Political Publications: vendredi idées, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Political Publications: "Philippe Sanmarco", 1993 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Ligue Communiste: Publications, undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Parti Socialiste: Publications, undated (Box 26, Folder 26)